Christian O. Valdes christian-valdes56@outlook.com | (956)715-6509



I seek a role where I can utilize my expertise and abilities to create or improve programs that can thrive in the global tech-driven economy, all while collaborating with experienced professionals.

Education

The University of Texas at Rio Grande Valley - Edinburg, TX

Aug 2019 - Dec 2023

GPA 3.93 | Major - Computer Science | Minor - Biology

South Texas College - McAllen, TX

Aug 2015 - May 2019

GPA 4.0 | Associates - Interdisciplinary Studies

Employment

Software Engineer, Intern - InvoiceCloud

June 2023 – Present

- Integrate tool to an existing website by first mocking the UI of the webpage and then developing it. Ensured connection to backend and retrieved data from database to create a responsive webpage. Documented progress through Jira stories.
- Create automated UI tests that would be added to the QA pipeline by adding necessary changes to the framework. Ensure that the data displayed to the UI represents what is in the database.

Assistant Researcher - UTRGV

Feb 2023 - Dec 2023

- Script movements for the Kuka robot KR 10 R1100 using the KUKA.Sim software as well as transfer the simulation onto the physical robot.
- Developing an app using Vuforia library in Unity to scan machines and display important features of them through the HoloLens 2.

Projects

Quadrupedal Autonomous Robot with Reinforced Learning

- Built a physical quadruped robot that consisted of 12 servos and ran through an NVIDIA Jetson Nano. Project simulation was done through ROS/Gazebo where a Deep-Q-Network was implemented to achieve walking motion. Controlling of the physical robot was achieved using ROS.
- Technology: Python based project that involved various software programs like PyTorch, ROS, and Gazebo.

E-Commerce Site

- Develop an E-commerce application using the .NET framework where you can purchase items using various methods of payments. Embed React to ease the UI aspect of the project and infuse database using SSMS to track backend requests respectively.
- Technology: Visual Studio and SSMS

Internship/Job Tracker

- Created an application where you could mark down any job-related occurrences and track them accordingly. Also implemented a basic tool that contained technical interview questions and kept progress. Primary goal was to try and create a purposeful login system so that each individual could only access and see their information/progress.
- Technology: Java based application that infuses SQL; IDE: Eclipse

Organizations & Awards

Spring 2023 - Present **Frontera Devs**

Purpose: Reach out to our community and inform/prepare them for the job world

SHPE Fall 2023 - Present

Purpose: Expose us to great companies and enrich us with what is needed to become a great professional

President's List Spring 2022 - Fall 2022 - Spring 2023

Recognition for achieving a grade point average of 4.0 for all courses taken in respective semester.

Languages

C++, Java, Python, Ruby, SQL, CSS, HTML, C#, VB

Software

Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Git, Github, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Linux, SSMS, React, Unity, .NET